http://probinso.dyn-o-saur.com

Personal Statement

I am currently a graduate student at Oregon Health and Sciences University, studying machine learning and statistical modeling. After completing my BS at Western Washington University, and my 4 years industry expirience, I have developed strong interests in cryptography, statistical computing, and programming languages. I am a very quick study, as I have adopted a new or tool-set in nearly every challenge I have taken on. My interest in teaching and writing has also gained me strong communication skills.

Language Experience :

* Python Julia Scala, Figaro Perl Ada C, C++ R ETEX

Education

Oregon Health Science University

CSLU

Computer Science MSc 2016 - present

Courses :

Machine Learning Information Retrieval Computing Ethics

Statistical Methods Univariate Statistical Analysis Analysis of Sequences

Western Washington University

Computer Science

Computer Science BS Mathematics Minor Sept. 2007 - June 2012

Electives :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Artificial Intelligence Natural Language Processing Functional Programming

Computer Graphics Computer Architecture Number Theory Elementary Real Analysis Linear Algebra I/II

Work Experience

Independent

- Contractor/Consultant

C&W Energy

Authored educational material in light pollution on economy, biology, and technology Light classification engine, custom photo image processing tools, and mathematical models Developed a memoizing data pipeline for caching computationally expensive operations

ComScore

June 2016 - Sept. 2016

Nov. 2015 - present

Worked to support large, custom, memory mapped, data store for demographic analysis

PDXCodeGuild

June 2016

Developed and taught introductory python course material for coding boot-camp

Melinae

March 2016

Setup infrastructure in AWS to enable secure sustainable workflow for remote company Provided hands on training in Python and R to industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++

Galois Inc.

- Research Engineer

April 2014 - Dec 2015

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track Developed technologies and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers Participated in programs sharing new technologies to research and industry professionals

Languages Used: Python, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker

EMC² Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Designed and developed password manager to support Data At Rest Encryption Wrote unit tests using libcheck to attain > 80% code coverage

Languages Used : C, C++, Python, SQLite

Computer Science Dept. - Mentors Program Director/Mentor Sept. 2009 - March 2012

Provided safe environment for training and instruction of students and mentors Ran student/faculty meetings to project future program responsibilities

Wrote comprehensive quarterly reports, and tools for automatic report generation

Languages Used: Ada, C++, Scheme, R

Neato Projects _____

Relivance Vector Machine Julia Sensor Systems and Light Pollution Analysis aws, sklearn, scipy, PonyORM, Python Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor R, caret Gradient Descent on Arbitrary Degree Hyperplanes Julia Probabilistic-Program Profiler and Evaluator Harness SLURM, PonyORM, Python Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Python Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Erlang, Sagemath Multilingual Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions R, Perl AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Ada Fractal Art Generator & Image Manipulation Program C# Unix Shell \boldsymbol{c}